[MUSIC]
Hi, I'm Sarah and I'm a program manager,
on the Engineering Education
team at Google.
As a program manager, I manage cross
functional teams on designing,
launching and growing Computer
Science Education Programs at Google.
So right now my primary remit and my scope
is essentially working with organizations
in New York City to try to provide
more tech education experiences and
growth opportunities to youth in the area.
During one of our biggest tech
education moments of the year,
one of the programs that I work on relies
on a third party's platform to be able
to run our activities and content.
And during a moment where
1000s of students and
teachers were getting ready to code
online, the platform completely broke.
And so you can imagine that
the number of emails and bugs and
requests that were coming
into our team were plentiful.
Don't panic.
Communicate openly and
quickly on the latter side of the issue.
Once you've already, kind of, fixed
the problem focus on a retrospective and
a clear post-mortem that's going to help
your team and then future teams be able
to prevent and mitigate something like
that from happening in the future.
I love retrospectives.
I do them all the time at Google just
because they're a great way to be able
to coalesce your entire team to look
at the great impact that you've had.
But then also reflect on some of
the things that you've learned and
could potentially do better for
the future.
And particularly at Google.
What I love about retrospectives
is that we have in engineering, and
then across a lot of other operational
roles, including project management,
a culture of blamelessness,
right?
If something goes wrong and
something breaks, instead of pointing at
your engineering team to say you weren't
prepared, or to point at your comms
team and say there was an error,
the whole team should be
taking responsibility.
And the whole team can actually look at
that as an opportunity to improve and
learn for future iterations
of what you're working on.
I've learned everything from big lessons
around the way that you should be building
more flexibility into your timeline,
to very, very small tactical changes that
you're going to need to make in order to
be running your project more effectively.
And so I think it's critical to be
capturing not only these very big
strategic level changes that
you might want to make.
But some of these small tactical things
you might be able to tweak to improve
efficiency going forward.
Sometimes when you have assumptions or
anticipations about the direction that
somethings going to go and then they
completely shift the other direction or
they show something completely
different than what you expected.
[SOUND]